#### Gail Kicks

201 Stewart Road, Bournemouth, Dorset, BH8 8PB M: 07493 031 289 E: gailkicks@aol.com

## **Personal Summary**

I consider myself to be a hard working and professional individual with numerous personal skills including; being well organised and able to manage others effectively, the ability to work on my own initiative and also as part of a team. I have shown that I am flexible in my general approach, willing to listen to the views of others, reliable and dependable. I am able to communicate effectively and professionally at all levels. Other qualities include patience, tolerance, understanding, empathy and a sense of humour.

I am a currently a Registered Service Manager with seventeen years' experience working with adults with learning disabilities and a variety of complex needs.

I have a good working knowledge of CQC regulations and standards and Priory policies, procedures and systems. I am able to mentor and support staff as well as establish and maintain effective working relationships with the people we support, their families and other professionals, giving constructive feedback when required.

## **Key Skills**

- Strong people and communication skills
- The ability to manage a budget and finances within set parameters
- Maintaining accurate records
- Completing audits and using the outcome of these to generate a live action plan
- Investigating any concerns in line with disciplinary policies and procedures
- Knowledge of relevant legislation and CQC standards, local services and resources
- The ability to build effective working relationships with a multi-disciplinary team
- Excellent IT skills
- Training staff in People Handling, Safeguarding and Diabetes

#### Career History

# The Tides July 2015 - Present and Anchor House April 2018 - Present Priory Service Manager

Anchor House is a home supporting seven individuals, with a staff team of fourteen and The Tides is a home supporting eight individuals with a staff team of twenty-one. I have full responsibility for the running of the Home, managing and developing the staff team and liaising with outside agencies and professionals to provide person centred care.

I work with the staff team, families, other professionals and outside agencies to plan and deliver care and support in line with current legislation and standards.

# April 2014 - July 2015, Ingleby House - Voyage Care, Service Manager

I managed Ingleby House where we supported four individuals with learning disabilities, in addition to a supported living flat where we supported one individual.

I managed a staff team of sixteen to provide person centred care with particular emphasis on promoting independence, dignity, privacy and safeguarding for the people we supported.

# September 2013 - March 2014, Priory - The Tides, Service Manager

See above

October 2012 - September 2013, Dorset County Council, Senior Care and Community Services Officer

# Jan 2012 - October 2012, Dorset County Council, Senior Care & Community Service Officer (Relief)

I assisted the Manager in the provision and development of services within the establishment and local community in line with CQC regulations along with management of staff, the building and budgets.

I had responsibility for a unit within the home where the people we supported had various needs, including individuals on the autistic spectrum. I produced and reviewed person centred support plans, reflecting service user's individual needs, liaising with outside agencies to provide the best possible quality of care. I managed the staff team within the unit, taking part in regular supervisions and unit meetings and maintaining a positive atmosphere.

August 2009 - October 2012, DRH Deputy Home Manager/Acting Home Manager

March 2008 - August 2009, DRH Senior Support Worker

September 2004 – March 2008, DRH Support Worker

#### **Training and Qualifications**

Diploma Level 5 in Health and Social Care

NVQ Level 4 Health and Social Care

Train the Trainer – Safeguarding, People Handling and Diabetes

Designated Safeguarding Lead

Safeguarding for Managers

Equality and Diversity for Managers

Epilepsy

Autism

All mandatory training completed

BSC Mathematics and Statistics – Sussex University

A-Levels: Mathematics and Statistics, Biology, Psychology and General Studies GCSEs: 9 GCSEs, A-C, including Mathematics, English and Science

#### References

Available on request